Guide to the Lucy Maynard Salmon Historical Materials Collection, 1690-1982 (bulk 1790-1899)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES XV. Correspondence
  - Emily Bliss to Miss Dulana Botsford, 9 Dec 1836; (typescript) (Box 19)
  - Isaac Bliss to Aunts and Cousins, 22 Apr 1837; (typescript) (Box 19)
  - S. Victor Constant to Willard L. Dean, 1885; (3 letters) (Box 19)
  - Simeon R. Curtis to Dulana Botsford, 12 Dec 1835; (typescript) (Box 19)
  - W.I. Cutter Correspondence, 1852-1854 (Box 19)
  - Alan Dimmick to Mother, 1848 (Box 19)
  - Alan Dimmick to Wife, 1862 (Box 19)
  - William Easton to Mr. West, 1862; (2 letters) (Box 19)
  - Michael Faraday to Constance, 1862 May 19; (2 letter, facsimile?) (Box 20 (Oversize))
  - John Fowler to Samuel Fowler (brother), 31 Aug 1814 (Box 19)
  - Betty Hey to parents, 18 Sep 1820; (typescript) (Box 19)
  - George Hogg Correspondence, 1863 (Box 19)
  - P.P. Hubbell to Loving Kate, 18 Jan 1875 (Box 19)
  - Alex Hunter to proprietors of Overland Monthly, 30 Nov 1870 (Box 19)
  - Letter of Ipswich Academy student to Kate Berry, 1836 (Box 19)
  - Letter of Ipswich Academy student to Nancy Everett, 1836; (typescript) (Box 19)
  - James A. Kirby to Lawrence Lewis, 18 July 1828 (Box 19)
  - Amos A. Lawrence – print of photograph of John Brown, undated (Box 19)
  - Robert P. MacCauley Correspondence, 1867-1870; (23 letters, 1 clippings) (Box 19)
  - "Old Rouse,", undated; (2 typescripts) (Box 19)
  - Phil to My "Own Darling,", 1851? (Box 19)
  - Franklin D. Roosevelt to Professor James Baldwin, 23 Sep 1938 (Box 19)
  - Harriet Beecher Stowe to Mrs. Follen, 16 Dec 1852 (Box 19)
  - Paul Allen Towne Correspondence, including material on defense of slavery, and political, military, social, and business situations during the Civil War with one response from his brother-in-law Dr. David Ransom on issue of state's rights and secession, 1860-1865; (14 letters, 2 typescripts) (Box 19)
  - Elizabeth J. Wood to Sister, 1847; (typescript only) (Box 19)
  - J.H. Wood to Mr. George Wright, 1842, 1844; (2 letters) (Box 19)
  - Margaret Young to Mrs. Henrietta Walker, 22 July 1899; (Photostat, typescript) (Box 19)
  - Letter of transmittal from Charles Wilson, the Secretary of the United States Legation, in Trinidad. Includes envelope, Oct 1861 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  - Letter commissioned by Queen Victoria, approving George Hogg as Consul to Trinidad, written and signed by Lord John Russell, 1861 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  - Papers of Rowley Family, [MISSING as of August 2007]
  - Letter of Mary Robinson, 1872; [MISSING as of August 2007]
  - Letters of Charles Hawley, 1857-1866; [MISSING as of August 2007]
  - Letter from Michigan State Prison, undated; [MISSING as of August 2007]
  - Letter of George Washington to Mr. William Hartshorne, 27 Oct 1799; (Photostat) [MISSING as of August 2007]
- SERIES XVI. Notebooks, Diaries, Journals, Scrapbooks, and Account books
  - Account Book, English — tithe book of collections from Glebe lands in English Parish, County Kent, 1732 (Box 1)
  - Album — Sarah Pope, 1834- (Box 1)
  - Diary of "Yankee Physician", 1831-1832 (Box 1)
  - Hadwen, Eliza A. — art in Rome, (2 MS) (Box 1)
  - Laundry List, Various dates (Box 1)
  - Notebook of Daniel Moore, circa 1819 (Box 2)
  - Self Indexing Scrap-Book (Box 6)
  - Scrapbook — green with picture of woman in bonnet on front (Box 6)
  - Copies of Charles Dickens journal entries (Box 6)
  - Commonplace Book - Jane Hood (Box 6)
  - Scrapbook of Mrs. Upton, wife to U.S. Consul in Geneva, Switzerland, 1863-1877 (Box 7)
  - Records of Central Committee of NY Yearly Meeting, 1870 (Box 7)
  - Journal of Bernard Mallon, 1848-1852 (Box 7)
  - Manuscript Sermons?, circa 1820 (Box 7)
  - Records of Missions Auxiliary, 1897-1901 (Box 7)
  - Notebook of Samuel Conklin (Poughkeepsie Justice of the Peace), circa 1773-1786 (Box 8)
  - Hattie, factory-operative in Franklin, New Hampshire — Diary, 1866 (Box 8)
  - 'What Can't be Cured Must be Endured': The Diary of a Mill Girl by Maureen O'Toole, a paper for History 367, 17 Nov 1982 (Box 8)
  - Copy of Extracts from Vassar diary of Elizabeth (Vinton) Pierce, ex-'76, Sep 1871-June 1872 (Box 8)
  - Botanical catalogue kept by F. Whittlesey, 1821-1825 (Box 9)
  - Two Old Account Books of Samuel C.T. Dodd (father of Marjorie Dodd MacCracken) (Box 9)
  - Sketch Album belonging to William Sewell, 1824 (Box 9)
  - Account book belonging to United States government?, 1824-1828 (Box 9)
  - Details re Bankrupts in Gloucester Journal and Farley's Bristol Journal 1774-1775, and small account of data in 1773-1775 questionnaire of emigrants (Box 10)
  - Envelope from Mallon Diary (Box 10)
  - Photocopy of A Brief History of the Dealings of God with Me in my Family from my Settlement to this day, 1824 (Box 10)
  - Through the Great West by G. Willis Morse, private journal, 1881?-1883 (Box 14 (Oversize))
  - Capen Account Ledger, 1813-1820 (Box 14 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook of the Presidential Election, Nov 1920 (Box 15 (Oversize))
  - A True Record of Mortality in the Town of Woodbury [Conn.], 1783-1853 (Box 16 (Oversize))
  - Scrapbook with comic clippings, 1880? (Box 16 (Oversize))
  - Ledger of accounts, Cleveland, Nov 1865-Apr 1867 (Box 16 (Oversize))
  - Household Accounts of Sarah Camden, 1800-1803 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Account Book of Job Rowley, undated (Box 19)
  - The Journal of Francis E. Pyle, 1860-1861; [MISSING as of August 2007]
- SERIES XVII. Land Documents and Deeds
  - Charter — a manorial charter supposed to have been made in the 9th year of Edward IV (with transcription by Professor James Baldwin) (Box 1)
  - Deed — Copy of deed 14 June 1864 property deeded to "Creator and God of Heaven (Box 1)
  - Deed (Box 1)
  - Deed — William Penn, typed copy, 1676 (Box 1)
  - Deed, 1806 (Box 1)
  - Deed, 1822 (Box 1)
  - Deed, 1845 (Box 1)
  - Land Patent — Louisiana (found among VC archival material in 1966), 24 Feb 1857 (Box 1)
  - Land Patent — Deed of Sale of confiscated estate New York City, 1785 (Box 1)
  - Land Patent — Granted by King George III to Neil McKinnin, New York City, Seal attached, 31 May 1771 (Box 1)
  - Land Patent — Release of Land at Hackensack, New Jersey, 1785 (Box 1)
  - Land Patent — Grant of land by Act of New York legislation to James Sherwood, signed by Governor Clinton, seal attached, 1790 (Box 1)
  - Letters patent to George Harrison, 20 July 1750 (Box 2)
  - Survey, 1812 (Box 2)
  - Survey — Milledgeville, GA (Box 2)
  - Land Grant to Thomas Brumfield by President Andrew Jackson and others, certificate no. 16.382, 1834 (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Handwritten Deed, 1598 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Resolution drawn up by the Newark Mountain Society to protect the land owned by members of the society against trespassers and the like, 19 Nov 1739 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Federal Land Grant signed by Martin Van Buren, 1820 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of transcript of land grant by William III to Thomas and Richard Willits, 10 Oct 1695 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of letter conveying the information of the purchase of Manhattan Island from the Indians by the Dutch. The original is in the Royal Archives at the Hague. It is the oldest known manuscript that relates to the local history of Manhattan, undated (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Deed of Sale, Massachusetts Bay, undated (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Land document, Massachusetts Bay, 14 June 1721 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Certificate of Clearance, Massachusetts Bay, 17 Apr 1783 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Land document, Massachusetts Bay, 1752 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Land document, Pelham, New York, 1821 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  - Deed signed by Daniel Boone, 13 Oct 1795; (Photostat, 2 copies) [MISSING as of August 2007]
- SERIES XVIII. Government materials
  - Commission, (positive Photostat) (Box 1)
  - Commissions – Postmaster (Box 1)
  - Constitution — Constitution of the United States of America, accompanied by certificate of W.A. Gresham, Secretary of State of the United States, that the document is a true copy from the archives of the Department, Washington, 1895. Seal of Dept of State is attached (Box 1)
  - Contract — Facsimile of the original Civil Compact [Providence, 1637] (Box 1)
  - Proclamation — call for volunteers – Spain, Washington, 1898 (Box 2)
  - Proclamation — Blackade of Cuban ports, Washington, 1898 (Box 2)
  - Parchment, ms, legal document, carta de poder, time of Don Carlos, Emperor and king of Germany and Donna Juan "Kings of Castille" written in Villalobrar with names Rodrigo Mateos and Alvaro Mateos, 1537-1547 (Box 16 (Oversize))
  - Conferral of naval rank of Lieutenant on Richard Forrest by John Tyler, 25 Feb 1841 (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - The pardon of Neal McElwee signed by President James Buchanan, 1858 (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Pardon of Humphrey Morrow signed by President Ulysses S. Grant, 1869 (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of President George Washington's Farewell Address, 1796 (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of Massachusetts documents including General Court: An Assessment of Rates, A Brief asking for contributions. (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of Pope Alexander VI Copia dela bul a de la concession ghizo U papa Alexandre selte (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Treaty of Versailles (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Jugement de M. le lieutenant generale de police de la ville de Soissons, 6 Nov 1769 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Extrait des minutes de le Secretaire D'Etat from palais le Milan, 21 Apr 1805? (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - The Pardon of Robert Rambo signed by Abraham Lincoln and Secretary of State Seward, 1862 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Dutch document commissioning C.F. Frank as captain, 30 Nov 1795 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Commission Surgeon's Mate in the Essex Brigade of the New Jersey Militia presented to Isaac Pierson… signed by Governor Joseph Bloomfield, 12 May 1807 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Commission of Sheriff of Essex County presented to Isaac Pierson, Signed by Joseph Bloomfield, 27 Oct 1808 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Document bestowing the rank of Ensign in the third company of foot in the second battalion of militia in the county of Northhampton, Pennsylvania, 1 May 1786 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - City of New York Common Council document, 28 Apr 1800 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Facsimile of King Charles I's Proclamation regarding tobacco trade, 6 Jan 1630-1631 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of Rhode Island General Assembly Act, 17 Sep 1787 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of Rhode Island Bill of Rights and Amendments to the Constitution, 1790 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of Newport, Rhode Island town-meeting minutes, 12 Jan 1774 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of Scheme of Lottery to enable funding a house for the Baptist Society in Providence, Rhode Island, 25 June 1774 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of notice "To the Freemen of the Colony…" Providence, Rhode Island, 19 Apr 1763 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of notice about election, Providence, Rhode Island, 31 March 1790 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of Ratification of United States Constitution by Rhode Island, 29 May 1790 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of notice to Rhode-Island and Providence Plantations, 31 May 1790 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of Proclamation by Arthur Fenner, Esquire, Governor of Rhode Island, 14 June 1790 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of Rhode Island General Assembly Vote, Sep 1790 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of Rhode Island General Assembly Act, June 1790 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of Constitution of Bank established at Providence Rhode Island, 3 Oct 1791 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of notice about electricity, Newport, Rhode Island, 16 March 1752 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of Catalogue of Books belonging to the town of Foster, Providence, Rhode Island, 24 Nov 1784 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of Proposals for printing a new weekly paper, Providence, Rhode Island, 26 Nov 1783 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of Rhode Island General Assembly Act, Providence, Rhode Island, Feb 1788 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of Rhode Island General Assembly, Oct 1788 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of Rhode Island Almanac, 1787 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of Wand, Samuel [Letter] to the Freemen of the Colony of Rhode Island, 1758? (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of Governor of Rhode Island Proclamation, undated (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of Rhode Island General Assembly Act, Sep 1789 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of Newspaper notice of Rhode Island Act, 9 Oct 1786 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostats of U.S. Constitution from originals in Rhode Island Historical Society and Brown University, undated (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Notice to sheriff concerning the estate and body of Peter Vinning (notice in the name of King George III), Massachusetts Bay, 17 May 1775 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Notice to sheriff concerning the estate and body of John Lambert (notice in the name of the government and people of the Massachusetts Bay in New England, all references to king have been crossed out), 5 Aug 1776 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Proclamation by Lieutenant Governor Francis Nicholson, Virginia, 20 Feb 1690; (slightly damaged on upper left hand corner, has been repaired) (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Ship's pass signed by Andrew Jackson and Martin Van Buren, 1830 (Box 19)
  - Note of leave for Alexander Smith, master of the brig named the Dauphin of Portsmouth. Signed by President George Washington, 27 May 1796 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  - Commission of the Honorable George Hogg, consul to Trinidad. Signed by President Abraham Lincoln and Secretary of State William H. Seward, 1861 (Mapcase - Drawer 37)
  - Decret de la Convention Nationtale, No. 1505, Sep 1793 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  - Decret de la Convention Nationtale, No. 1555., Sep 1793 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  - Decret de la Convention Nationtale, No. 1622, Oct 1793 (Box 20 (Oversize))
  - Ordannance de Police, June 1757 (Mapcase - Drawer 37)
  - Ordinances and other records of the town or borough of Elizabeth, New Jersey, 1774-1778; [MISSING as of August 2007]
  - Proclamation of royal governor, Massachusetts, 17 June 1763; (Photostat) [MISSING as of August 2007]
- SERIES XIX. Wills, Legal Documents and Business Papers
  - Bills (Box 1)
  - Business Records (Box 1)
  - Business Records (estate of Strong Hayden) (Box 1)
  - Documents, Legal — Old German legal document dated Marbury, 27 Dec 1706 (Box 1)
  - Farm Records (Box 1)
  - Inventory (Box 1)
  - Inventory (English) – of Mrs. Temple, 1690-1710 (Box 1)
  - Note (promissory), 21 Dec 1782 (Box 2)
  - Randall, Phillip (New England Farmer) — inventory of goods, 1662 (Box 2)
  - Share — Speculation Oil Co., sample of shares sold by "Sandy River Petroleum Prize Co." (evidently a speculation enterprise) and state-bank bill of 1857 – Massachusetts – Worcester Co. – See Money, Paper, 1868 (Box 2)
  - Slave Receipts (Box 2)
  - Slave Receipt (slave bill of sale) Poughkeepsie, 1803 (Box 2)
  - Will of Richard Chamberlain, 1727 (Box 2)
  - Will of Jacob Kip, 21 Feb 1731; (typescript only) (Box 2)
  - The Estate of Mary Reid (Folder 11.13)
  - Translation of Dutch of Will of Jacob Kip (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Article of Indenture of Joseph Willis to Daniel Willis, 8 May 1788 (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Marriage Certificate of Arnold Greene and Caroline Austin (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Indenture Papers, 1676 (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Indenture Papers, 1695 (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Document, 1629 (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Receipt for £26-2-6 signed by Richard Moore, Charleston, 6 Sep 1796 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Draft on the Newark Bank for $1050.00, 10 July 1809 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Certificate of Stock-holder in Orange Library Association, 10 March 1858 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Tailor's Bill itemized and receipted, 14 July 1827 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Demand Note, for $31.58, receipted on back for part payment, 1811 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Torn part of note for $126. (?), receipted on back, 1811 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Note of John Condit to Betsy Condit for £8-2-9, 9 Jan 1796 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - $20.00 Reward for runaway slave named Caesar by John Halsey, 23 Apr 1808 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - First payment in the purchase of one share of stock in the Newark and Mount Pleasant Turnpike Co., 21 March 1806 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Receipt of twelve shillings from Isaac Pierson to Henry Taylor, 1803 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Subscription for Newspaper to Henry Van Winkle from Isaac Purfon, 1 Jan 1809 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Receipt of $30.00 for Riding Chair, 24 Aug 1805 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Receipt for four dollars signed by William L ?, 20 Feb 1809 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Memorandum of payment due Samuel Bell from Mathias Pierson, 28 May 1810 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Document admitting John Morrison, a merchant of Dumferling, to the Gild Council of the city of Glasgow, 13 Apr 1750 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - A court document settling some technical difficulty between and owner and his slave, 28 Sep 1827 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Legal Document outlining the decision in a case founded on a debt of four dollars and some few cents, 14 May 1810 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Contract between John Blanchard and Isaac Pierson involving the sale of a negro slave, 10 June 1802 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Manumission paper releasing a slave at the beginning of the next year, 9 Aug 1813 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Contract between Isaac Van Saun and Isaac Pierson, 1 Jan 1814 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - A Receipted Grocer's bill, Feb-Aug 1810 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Surrogate's certificate of last will and testament of Matthias Pierson and authorization for administration of estate, 19 Sep 1809 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Last Will and Testament of Matthias Pierson, transcript from court record, 9 Apr 1799 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Matthew Vassar's bills, letters, drafts, 1822, 1825 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Photostats of 3 indenture papers, one Photostat of document related to Charles II, undated (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Documents relating to Hays family, including later obituary of one member, 1828-1841, undated (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Articles of agreement between George Washington and Philip Bater, 23 Apr 1789; (Photostat) [MISSING as of August 2007]
  - Inventory of Justin Loomis, a lunatic, NY Supreme Court, 12 March 1849; [MISSING as of August 2007]
  - A return of slaves in the Parish of Saint Ann [Jamaica], 1817-1823 (Box 20 (Oversize))
- SERIES XX. Miscellaneous Items and Realia
  - Advertisements (Box 1)
  - Broadsides (Box 1)
  - Dutchess County (Box 1)
  - Education, Secondary (Box 1)
  - Handbills — "Ploughs, Ploughs", 1 March 1849 (Box 1)
  - Local history of Elmira, New York, illustrated by photographs, maps, Indian arrowheads, beads and other relics together with an account of the same by H.C. Neef of the class of 1897 (Box 2)
  - Manuscript — BM Sloan, (Negative Photostat) (Box 2)
  - Money, paper (Box 2)
  - Olive Branch Petition, (facsimile) (Box 2)
  - Patent (plow), 1871 (Box 2)
  - Pemaquid Beach, ME (Box 2)
  - Signatures — facsimiles of signatures to the preliminary articles of Peace with the Senecas, 14 Apr 1754; (2 copies) (Box 2)
  - Tracts, Religious (Box 2)
  - Roster, 1812 (Box 2)
  - A piece of drapery of the bed of Napoleon I at Longwood, St. Helena, (framed) (Box 6)
  - Flower sketches (Box 6)
  - Photograph of Helen Kenyon? (Box 6)
  - Camera accessory, function unknown (Box 6)
  - Paper furniture of Hannah S. Hallock. Furniture for three rooms, with some pieces missing, circa 1855 (Box 6)
  - 2 boxes of Medals and plaques (Box 6)
  - Graduation certificate Vassar College — Elizabeth Josephine Schieblick (Box 6)
  - Coe's New Drawing Cards for Schools no. 9 (Box 6)
  - Receipt books for gifts to the collection, 1939-1942, 1951-1952 (Box 6)
  - Package of color prints of mosses, flowers, etc said to have been printed by Prang before 1869, (in box labeled Schrafft's) (Box 6)
  - The History of Little Goody Twoshoes, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Child's toys, bellows and ottoman made of small shells brought from Italy by Matthew Vassar and given by him to a child friend, Frederica Davis, (in box labeled Guth) (Box 6)
  - Miss 'Prentiss' Wedding (An Account by Mrs. John H. Raymond, Wife of President Raymond, formerly Cornelia E. Morse) (Box 8)
  - The Old House…Cutchoque, NY with notes (Box 8)
  - Seal of unknown commission (Box 9)
  - Indian arrowhead (Box 9)
  - Indian Relics (Box 9)
  - Daboll poems, essay, circa 1820s (Box 10)
  - A Journey by Annie Ogden, 10 Jan 1872 (Folder 11.1)
  - The Picnic by Annie Ogden, 28 June 1870 (Folder 11.1)
  - Books by Annie Ogden, 19 Feb 1875 (Folder 11.2)
  - Coral by Annie Ogden, 6 Feb 1872 (Folder 11.2)
  - A Journey from Chicago to San Francisco by Annie Ogden, 16 Jan 1872 (Folder 11.2)
  - Orion by Annie Ogden, 27 March 1874 (Folder 11.2)
  - Penelope by Annie Ogden, 8 March 1874 (Folder 11.2)
  - Coffee by Annie Ogden, 1871 (Folder 11.2)
  - The Rock and the Reel by Annie Ogden, 24 Jan 1872 (Folder 11.3)
  - Translation and transcript of decree (Folder 11.7)
  - Ornaments by Annie Ogden, 19 March 1872 (Folder 11.8)
  - Grace by Annie Ogden, 3 May 1873 (Folder 11.8)
  - Something about Pearls by Annie Ogden, 1Feb 1873 (Folder 11.8)
  - Oranges by Annie Ogden, 24 March 1875 (Folder 11.8)
  - Two unknown works (Folder 11.8)
  - A Story by Annie Ogden, 30 Dec 1871 (Folder 11.8)
  - Laughter by Annie Ogden, 19 Dec 1876 (Folder 11.8)
  - John Ogden Memorial Committee, 24 June 1913 (Folder 11.9)
  - Work by Annie Ogden, 29 Oct 1873 (Folder 11.10)
  - Daedalus by Annie Ogden, 8 May 1874 (Folder 11.11)
  - Hercules by Annie Ogden, 24 Apr 1874 (Folder 11.12)
  - The Great Clock of Strashing by Annie Ogden, 12 Aug 1871 (Folder 11.14)
  - Spartan Education by Annie Ogden, 5 Oct 1876 (Folder 11.15)
  - A Visit to the Academy of Sciences by Annie Ogden, 28 Nov 1870 (Folder 11.16)
  - Diamonds by Annie Ogden, 18 Apr 1871 (Folder 11.16)
  - A Description of the Fire by Annie Ogden, 28 Nov 1871 (Folder 11.19)
  - Tea by Annie Ogden, 1871 (Folder 11.19)
  - Watches by Annie Ogden, 12 Dec 1871 (Folder 11.19)
  - Pearls by Annie Ogden, 20 Feb 1872 (Folder 11.19)
  - Balloons by Annie Ogden, 10 Apr 1872 (Folder 11.19)
  - Water by Annie Ogden, 22 Dec 1874 (Folder 11.21)
  - The Automaton Chessplayer by Annie Ogden, 8 May 1872 (Folder 11.21)
  - Flowers by Annie Ogden, 4 Dec 1871 (Folder 11.21)
  - Cotton by Annie Ogden, 18 Apr 1872 (Folder 11.21)
  - Salt by Annie Ogden, 14 May 1872 (Folder 11.21)
  - Slang by Annie Ogden, 21 Oct 1876 (Folder 11.22)
  - Feminine Occupations by Annie Ogden, 17 June 1875 (Folder 11.22)
  - Unidentified material on children's books (Box 13)
  - Manuscript sermon written by Rev. Ebenezer Gay, Sr. and delivered in Suffield, Conn., 31 May 1775 (Box 16 (Oversize))
  - Photostats of material relating to Brown University (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of proposals for printing by subscriptions, two sermons preached on Sunday 29 December 1799- (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of George Whitfield materials including: a Funeral Sermon, A Funeral Elegy on George Whitfield, The Dying Speech of William Linsey, Phillis's Poem on the death of Mr. Whitfield, The Columbian Tragedy: Verses on the Sudden Death of 6 Young Women and One Boy (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Photostat of Siege de Nameur print (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - Recipe for medicine (Box 17 (Oversize))
  - List of documents (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - One dollar bill of State of North Carolina, 1 Jan 1866 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Two dollar bill of Confederate States of America, 17 Feb 1864; (2 items) (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Three dollar bill of The Orange Bank of Orange New Jersey, 1 Jan 1856 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Visiting card of Wilham Ingraham Kip, 1822 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Diploma, 1789 (Box 18 (Oversize))
  - Proclamation by William Lyon MacKenzie, 13 Dec 1837 (Box 18 (Oversize))